Hello friends, welcome to TP Insights.
In today's video, we will talk
about hospital empanelment. Hospital
empanelment means that you can link your
hospital with any insurance company, that is, you
can join its network, be it ADFC Ergo,
ICICI Lord, Care Health, Tata
AIG, or any of these insurance companies or
TPAs. How
can you link your hospital with their network
so that your hospital is
shown in their network list and patients of all those companies can
come to you and get cashless treatment
because you will be able to get cashless treatment only
when your hospital is linked with that insurance company or
TPA, that is,
your hospital will be linked to their network hospital, only then
you can make a cashless claim to it.
Before making this video, I
made a video for you people that you
want to learn the work of TPA, so
many people got positive comments about it,
some people also showed a lot of trust, so for
all of them, I have started this first video today.
Gradually, I will
bring more videos for you people from the beginning.  I will
start making videos about
how the process happens from the beginning till the end
so that no one has any confusion
and everything becomes clear and
you people do not face any problem in working. The
main purpose of making videos is that
many new people who come to TPA have to
face many problems, so
I
want to tell those people as well as all those who are working that
if you want to learn the work of TPA by watching videos, then you will
never be able to do it. Yes, through videos you will get
some guidance on how to
work and what things to keep in mind. So the more
you do practical work in TPA work, the
better it will be for you because after watching the video it will seem
very easy, but but
in reality when you process the claim, many such
problems will come up which will
not be in the video, you will have to
handle them according to the situation and I will cover most of the things
in the video
so that you can work well and
You guys should not have any problem, still if you
guys have any problem then you can
write to me in the comment section of the video or you can do it on
my whatsappwap.in, that is, you
can add it, so it is called
hospital empanelment and it is
called hospital empanelled list, that is the
hospitals which are already connected, so
you guys have to add your hospital, so that is why it will be
called hospital empanelment, to
teach the work of TPA, I am making a separate
playlist in which I will
put the topic that how you guys
can do the process of TPA, so you guys
can watch this video by going to that, so further in this video I am going to show
you guys on the screen, I am going to
go to their website and show you the
insurance company, how you guys
can connect your hospital with that company
or you can work by joining those insurance companies,
you
can provide service to their customers, so I will show you guys in full detail on the
screen, so
in the video, you guys should stay till the end
on the channel, if you guys are new then subscribe to the channel,
press the bell icon so that
you guys keep getting notifications of new videos, so let's watch
the video  Let's start
[Music]
All
insurance companies and TPAs ​​have set their own
criteria for hospital empanelment, meaning
they have set certain document criteria
that you need,
like the number of
beds, the total number of beds, the maximum, like the
minimum should be 15, the maximum can be as many, there is
a Rohini ID, which is
mandatory, and the
doctors there should have the
qualification of MD, MS, etc.,
and your nursing staff should be
qualified, ANM B.Sc.
Nursing, which
means they should have the qualification, and there is
an NBH, its certificate is also mandatory,
so this is a criteria for
certain documents that
all insurance companies and TPNs have set. So, first of all,
I want to tell you that for the
network hospital that we have to add, for that, first of all,
I want to tell
you about Star Health Insurance Company. So, the first thing
we have to do is go to the box and
type Star Health.
Here we will write Star
Health, we will write Star Health, so
first of all the website that will open up,
we have to click on this,
we have to put it in desktop mode
so that it
opens like the system, now
we have to move down, slowly scroll
it
and here an option of network will
appear, we have to move down also,
see in this, here the search pin code of the
hospital will appear, the hospital which you have to
search, that is, the one which
is already there in the network list and the one which we have to
register new, will appear here,
new network hospital
empanelment, here there will be empanelment
of the new hospital, if you click on this then
a new window will open here,
see I have clicked on this,
after that this empanelment criteria will appear,
see minimum 10 bed bays of multi-
specialty, so you people have to read this,
many things are written in terms in it, the more
carefully you read it, the less
problem you will face, if you do
not have any idea about this then the
doctors of your hospital or the
medical  If there is a team or the management, then
you people will have to take help from them
because there are many things in it which are
related to medical and the TPA
people who do not even know, they get a little confused, so it is
not possible to explain each and every thing in this video, when you do it by
clicking on it, when you will read it or see it or if
you take help from other friends who do some work, then you will get the
solution in it, so
this type of criteria has been given by
them here, this criteria here,
below this criteria,
all the details are written, what all
they want, after that this is for
rural, this one is for rural and
above this, this one is for urban and metro,
which is the criteria, so now we have to
move ahead in this and see below, we have to tick here,
I oblige we have read the
empanelment criteria, we have
read the criteria of empanelment and now
we have to move ahead in this by ticking it, so
here we have to click on the empanelment form,
as soon as we click on the form, it will appear for
us  This form will open in front of you. Now
what is written in it that online empanelment
facility will be available from first to
fifth of every month. They are saying that
you can apply from 1st to 5th of any month to
add your hospital, that is,
for empanelment. Their portal will be
available only from 1st to 5th. So
you people have to keep in mind that whenever you want to apply to
add your hospital for Star Health,
you people have to keep it
between 1st to 5th
or note it down in your diary somewhere.
Their window opens at this time. When its
complete form opens, for that you people will have to
keep your documents in PDF first,
like the registration number of the hospital
and the PAN card of the hospital, the
photos of the
owner, that is, the
ID of the doctors there, etc.
So all the documents have to be made in PDF in advance
or kept in JPG by making absolutely clear
photos so that you people can fill this form quickly.  By
filling it and uploading the documents that are asked for there,
now in the next video I will
tell you about another insurance company
HDFC Ergo.
We have to go to its website
where we
can add our hospital to their network list.
So we have to go back from here and
search for HDFC
Ergo, ADFC Ergo. As we search for it, we do not have to
click on the first one. This is the first website, we do not have to click on it.
We have to go to the second one, that is, we have to go to this website. If we
click on this, then
we will directly go to the ADFC Ergo website. From
here we have to check once
whether it is in desktop mode or not. If it is
not in desktop mode, then it will be
in desktop mode, that is, the
website will open in the same way as we open it on our laptop or PC. After this, we have to
go to the very last one. We have to
click here and
see here, this option is coming in it. See, here
we have to click on Hospital Empanelment Form.
As soon as we click on it,
this form will open in front of us.  It will appear in
it like the name of the provider, the
name of the hospital, in this also you have to keep
all the documents ready first,
as you fill in the details, you will keep
filling in whatever is asked for, then it will
open in front of you, the
link of all these insurance companies, that is, the
link of the form, I am
giving it in the description of this video so that you
people do not face any problem in finding it,
now I am telling you how to do it for the next insurance company, that
is Care
Health, we have to go to the website of Care Health,
now we have to directly write Care Health here,
Care
Health Insurance,
so the second website in this, the second
number website,
we have to click on it, as soon as we click on it,
this website will open in front of us, it is
already in desktop mode here,
so we have to go to the very last in it, at the
very last,
see here, see hospital empanelment, this is coming,
see this option, we have to click on it, as
soon as we click on it, a new
window will open in front of us, in this
you can see the criteria here,
hospital  Element criteria means
what documents will you people need,
what criteria will they need for the
care health people, all of that will be
written inside it, if you people have already made a
request, then you
can track your
request on track request here and if you want to send a new request, then you
can send a new request by clicking here,
upload document, here the
option of uploading document is coming below, you
can upload the document, after this
what we have to do first is we have to
send a new request, so we
will click on new request, as soon as the
form will open in front of us, name of
the hospital, address, pin code, then
as you keep clicking next in it,
communication details, certification details,
finance details, other empanelment held
currently specified with names, all of them will keep
opening, so for this also you
people already have to keep the documents of your
hospital ready, by making it in PDF etc.,
you people have to fill whatever details they ask for  One thing I
want to tell you is that as you
submit this, if any document remains
incomplete, it will be
asked for later through mail or on the
portal itself. There will be an option to upload any
document. Now when
you check, you will know about it,
but the process will at least start.
You have to apply for this by going to the website as well.
After this, we have to apply for
ICICI Lombard, which is the number four
insurance company, that is, the one
I am going to tell you about at number four. For that,
we have to write ICICI Lombard here. If you
write ICICI Lombard Health Insurance Hospital Empanelment, then
this page will open directly in front of you.
When you click on it, this form will open in front of you.
You have to
fill in the details in this form. Look, a lot of
details are asked here. You have to see them and
fill them carefully. The things that have been
filled in it, but perhaps you will
not be able to make changes in them, so you have to fill in the details very carefully and
wisely.
Regarding the facilities,
you people have to prepare a sheet in Excel in advance as to
which facilities are there, whether they are
multi-specialty or some particular
facilities are available, so apart from this,
you people should know about this thing in advance, so
this is the
form of ICICI Lombard, I will also give you the link of this
in the description,
after that the next insurance companies TPA
is Paramount TPA, so Paramount P P
as soon as you people search Paramount P here, the
website will come up at the top,
after that we have to click here on
three dots, then
Network Hospital is written here,
see Network Hospital,
when we click on it here, in
front of Network Hospital,
see here, click here, when
we click here, the
list of hospital networks will come up here and it is written
Enroll in Network, that is, you
can enroll, you can join our
network, so here we have to click on this, as soon as we
click on this, a new window will
open in front of us.  It will come, see, here is the
hospital guide, all the things are written in it,
you can read it, after reading
you have to fill all the things which are being
asked for in it, the
option of uploading the documents is also coming
and if you submit it here, then you will get
an application number and
you can also track it with it or
you can also find out by talking to the customer care
that brother, what is the status of our empanelment, if you have an
email ID, then you can also
enter your application number in it and
you can also enter the reminder etc. By the way, the ones which are
online have a tracking
number, so you can also track that, then there will be
no problem, so I have told you people about these five
insurance companies, which were the biggest and
famous insurance companies, so
in today's video,
in today's video I
told you people how you
can connect your hospital with the network hospital of the insurance company, that is,
you can do the work of hospital empanelment,
you can
go to the website at the top of the screen and know about each and every thing in complete detail
about the five insurance companies  I have
told you that if you
can learn the work of these five insurance companies, that is, you
can do the work of empanelment, then you can do the work of other
insurance companies in a very easy way,
you will
not face any problem, still if you face any problem then
you can write to me in the comment section and
I will reply to you or
you can
whatsapp me on web, if you liked it then like the video,
subscribe to the channel and
press the bell icon so that you keep getting notifications of new videos, so
that's all for today's video, till then,
hello in the next video.